[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Hm.  I better reload.
Never know when I'll be making
new friends around here.
Huh, we've got so many dead bodies,
we're hanging them from the ceiling now.
And the ceiling eats them.
Guess that works.
Wha-hoah!
That shock just got the face-hugger!
And another one!
Will this guy make it?
No!
You're all popcorn.
That really does have
to be more than coincidence.
I mean--GYAH!
[explosion]
Okay, I guess I'm not going that way.
Where am I going?
The blood trail's
gone up into the ceiling.
Ah!
"Administrative offices..."
Yeah, no exit!
No one leaves here.
What's that say?
"Work harder, not smarter."
Yeah, that's us, alright.
We stay the course with stupid.
Hey, there's somebody in there.
[scientist screaming]
Hey, quit screwing around
and open the door!
Come on!
The door's locked, assholes!
Dammit!
Y'know, it's hard to believe we won
the Cold War with initiative like that.
That's not the spirit that kept
Soviet paratroopers off my lawn.
If somebody knocks on the door, you
don't run away and go play with aliens.
Ah, an air vent.
Die Hard has shown me the way once again.
Now we're making progress.
I think.
What?
BUG!
This is MY air vent.
Hey, this is a dead end.
And so are you!
DIE DIE DIE DIE DIE!
These bugs think they own the place.
Well, there's going to be some
restructuring around here.
Oh, there's another one.
That's right.
Keep running, you little bastard.
I see you thinking
you're going to escape.
Well, you're WRONG!
Just like everyone else here!
RRAAAAAH!
Man, today is so counterintuitive
to everything I did in grad school.
I would shout and break stuff there,
too, but that never got anything done.
So, what's the deal
with--AAHHH...
Grody!
I hate this place.
[pattering sound]
What's that noise?
Ugh, that makes not even want to
loot the machine now.
I was going to grab some Doritos
or something.
Oh, but look who it is.
[ceiling tiles fall]
What?
Don't interrupt me.
The man who can't open the door.
SCIENTIST: Gordon...
Yes?
SCIENTIST: If I had known it was
you, I'd have let you in.
Of course.
SCIENTIST: Everyone's heading
for the surface.
SCIENTIST: But I think they're
crazy not to stay put.
SCIENTIST: Someone is bound to
come by and rescue us.
Well, I believe you.
But, does my gun believe you?
Oh, all right.
I'll let you live, but you're on
the preliminary list.
What's this?
"High voltage"?
Cool.  Maybe I can fry those
things hanging from the ceiling.
Oh, that turned it off.
Oh well.
I wonder if that guy's right
about--Don't puke on me.
--that guy's right about waiting here.
I would feel stupid if there was a
rescue team waiting in the lobby.
All right, looks like that cut the power.
Now, I can pass safely, proving once
again that I am superior to aliens.
And everyone.
[whistling]
[lock jiggles]
What?!
I WENT THROUGH THAT
OBSTACLE COURSE FOR THIS?!
I HATE THIS BUILDING!
I WANT TO SMASH THE WHOLE THING DOWN!
[glass shatters]
Oh, well that works.
Maybe I should
become a burglar after this.
I'm getting the hang of breaking-
and-entering and I like stealing stuff.
Wow, glad that's not my lab.
"Scheduled Chaos Theory"?
That makes as much sense as
"Grounded Aviation".
Or "Deep Sea Astronomy".
[locks jiggle]
Of course.
Every door is locked.
Always.
Why is every door locked?
This is a workday.
It's not like I'm breaking out
on Sunday evening.
Ah!  Thought I didn't see you, huh?
I'm watching.  I'm always watching.
Well, the sign was right.
This looks like storage.
Another dead end.
This must be the prep room
for the crate-smashing room.
Crate City: For All Your
Creative Crate Needs
[growls]
Y'know, I'm torn between wanting to
kill every single bug in this building
or just leveling it with explosives.
I need a bomb.
Nah, that's probably a janitor closet.
This window kind of reminds me
of when I came home from school
and there was some dead guy stuck
in the smashed window of my apartment.
He had been trying to break into the place,
but instead gutted himself on
the insulated glass.
That was not fun trying to
explain that to the police.
Oh, what's that?
Another air vent.
These people locking doors think
they're smart, but they're not.
Guess I'd better clear out all
this glass, first.
I'm kind of like glass, in a way.
I'll tear people to shreds when
I can't do my job.
All right, so, this is not
very comfortable.
[screaming]
Okay!  That water's got some
electricity running through it.
I didn't really plan for that,
but, that's okay.
That's okay.
I can do this.
I just need a breather for a second.
Yeah, I can do this.
Hell, I've gotten hit with
Tasers that do more than that.
Women are too damned jumpy with
those things.
I swear, half the dates I go on,
it's just 'zap'.
That's not as bad as pepper
spray, though.
God, I hate pepper spray.
[shuddering]
[exhaling]
Oh, you son of a bitch.
[ringing]
Gyeeeeaaaaaaggggghhhh...
My ears!
[ringing]
That was not smart.
Firing a gun inside an air vent...
[ringing]
I hope I'm not deaf...
I need a silencer.
[ringing]
And that whole electrical shock thing
reminds me of that guy I used to know.
[ringing fades]
What was his name?
Jessie.  He was crazy.
He would--eugh.
He would lie on his bed then
drop a cattle-prod on his leg
with the voltage set so high he would
just be paralyzed there for an hour or two.
He did that all the time for fun.
Personally, I could think of better ways
to spend an evening--AH SHIT!
Yep, whoever designed this
building did not count on me.
[ceiling tiles fall]
Oh, copy cats!
Forgot to copy that move, huh?
Actually, I'd better shut up.
It would be just my luck for these
aliens to figure out how to use guns.
Any more takers?
No?
All right, let's--
[lock jiggles]
--cry...
This locked door thing is
getting real old.
Ay yi yi yi yi yi...
What now?
Well, back to crawling in the
ceiling like a voyeur.
[Steve Irwin accent]
Ah, the hunter spots his prey.
He takes aim.
[heacrab squeals]
Crikey!
And that's about as close as it gets!
[regular accent]
Now what are aliens doing up here, anyway?
I guess they must've teleported in,
but how do they know where to go?
Ohh, maybe they don't!
Maybe they're teleporting into the walls.
That could be why
the building's falling apart.
We're turning into the
Swiss Cheese of the Damned.
Wait, what if one teleported inside me?
Oh, geez, I don't think
I could take that.
[whistling noise]
Whoa, what happened here?
[turret firing]
Agh! God!  Jeez!  Shit!
What was that?!
[turret firing]
Who's firing?!
[turret beeps]
Did I get hit?
I don't see any blood.
[turret beeps]
If I could just see--
[turret firing]
FUCK!
[turret beeps]
It's like...
It's like a turret gun or something.
[turret firing]
You okay?
[turret beeps]
Eh, I don't care.
Jesus Christ!
[turret beeps]
Oh, some clips, I'll take that.
Yes!  An exit.
[turret beeps]
Oh my God! This is where I just came from!
Maybe that's why all the doors are locked.
[turret deactivates]
To keep people like me from
wandering into a firing range.
Hey, want to be my human shield?
SCIENTIST: Shut up!
It was just an idea.
Um... no, that's just a dead end.
Maybe I could force him out
there if I waved my gun at him.
SCIENTIST: Oh-ooooh...!
Shit, did I say that out loud?
[whistling noise]
Yep, it's still there.
[turret firing]
[turret beeps]
Okay.
Well, this is about as good a time
[turret beeps]
to take a break as any.